# Calvin Chun-Yu Chan

Senior Software Engineer

hello@calvincchan.com Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada Web: <u>calvincchan.com</u> Github: <u>github.com/calvincchan</u> Linkedin: <u>linkedin.com/in/calvincchan</u>



## **INTRO**

My experience working at startups has taught me to build quickly, learn from mistakes, and embrace change based on feedback and validation. I have implemented practical solutions for various business requirements, built API servers, developed web and mobile clients, managed cloud infrastructure and container orchestration using Docker, and prepared automated deployment pipelines. I strongly believe AI is the future and am passionate about applying it to products to drive innovation, enhance user experiences, and improve productivity.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Founding Software Engineer - EDU.INK Limited (Hong Kong)**

Jun 2019 - Present

#### **Impacts**

- Led the development of a real-time collaborative CMS using React, Refine.js framework, and Supabase / PostgreSQL to provide secure information collaboration and role-based permission among learning support team members.
- Led the development of all major products, including a student information system, admission and enrolment, billing and online payment, and parent-teacher communication platform.
- Led the transition from the legacy monolithic PHP Laravel app to a client-server architecture with Node.js and MongoDB backend, Vue.js frontend, and React Native mobile apps. This resulted in dramatic improvements in service quality, development speed and maintainability.

#### Responsibilities

- Collaborate with clients and business team to elicit requirements and design prototypes.
- Researched and evaluated new tech stacks and applied them to product developments.
- Design and implement micro-services and clients quickly to iterate based on feedbacks.
- Coordinate with 2 React Native developers to manage the iOS/Android mobile app development, testing, deployment and release pipelines on both platforms.

#### **Technology**

Node.js, Javascript/Typescript, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Jest, Supabase / PostgreSQL, Docker, Fastify, Restify, Express.js, OpenAPI, Stripe, Active Directory, OneSignal, Vue.js (v2), React.js, Material UI, refine.js, React Native, CircleCl, BitBucket Pipeline, AWS EC2, AWS Lambda, Docker, AWS S3, Google Cloud Platform, Axure RP, Adobe Illustrator

# Founding Software Engineer - GUZZU Limited (Shenzhen, China)

Jun 2016 - Sep 2019

#### **Impacts**

- Implemented an expat-focused e-commerce platform with a bilingual interface to help
  English-speaking business owners manage their businesses and serve Chinese customers.
- Built WeChat mini-programs that allow merchants to engage easily with local customers.
- Collaborated with an Android developer to create a merchant POS terminal prototype.
- Built a mobile-web event ticket sales platform, including a management backend and a barcode scanning ticket validation app.

#### Responsibilities

- Directed a small team in developing the Node.js API servers, mobile web clients and WeChat mini programs.
- Engaged with local expat merchants to strategize new products and features.

### **Technology**

Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, Redis, Vue.js, WeChat Mini Program SDK, Aliyun Cloud

# **Contract Software Engineer - archiparti.co (Hong Kong)**

Apr 2015 - Apr 2016

Built an information system to manage interior design projects.

## **Technology**

Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, Angular.js, AWS

# Founding Software Engineer - giftpass.cn (Shanghai, China)

Mar 2013 - Jun 2015

As a team in the Chinaccelerator startup incubator program, I designed and implemented a digital gift voucher platform and mobile app that simplifies the management and consumption lifecycle for consumers and merchants. Rapidly built proof-of-concept projects and MVPs.

## **Technology**

Node.js, Javascript, MongoDB, Apple Wallet SDK, Angular.js, WeChat, Aliyun Cloud

## **UX Designer - Genesix Inc. (Japan)**

May 2011 - Jul 2012

Worked with product managers and iOS engineers on a voice-based instant messaging app with positive user feedback and market interest in Southeast Asia. Contributed to mobile web marketing projects, designed user experiences, interfaces, and visual elements for iOS and mobile web apps, and conducted user interviews and research.

#### **Technology**

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, jQuery Mobile

# Web Designer and Engineer - A.C.O. Inc. (Japan)

Sep 2010 - Mar 2011

Contributed to building websites for clients using web design, rapid prototyping, and UI engineering skills with Adobe Fireworks and jQuery. Developed a Facebook Page and social application for global marketing initiatives, increasing brand awareness and user engagement.

# **Technology**

Adobe Fireworks, Adobe Photoshop, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery

# InnateDB Software Developer - The University of British Columbia (Canada)

Mar 2007 - Jun 2010

Designed and implemented the search engine frontend for researchers to submit queries and interact with the database. Collaborated with DB admins and project managers to build the frontend. Implemented data visualization and report generation features.

#### **Technology**

Javascript, CSS, jQuery, HTML, PHP, CakePHP, MySQL

#### **VOLUNTEER**

# **Board Member - Familogue Education Society - familogue.ca (Canada)**

Sep 2024 - Present

Built automated e-transfer handling for order confirmation, internal member information system, bookkeeping software integration, custom time-tracking feature.

## **Technology**

TS/JS, SCSS, Supabase / PostgreSQL, React, React.js, Material UI, refine.js

#### Integration

Square Payment, Simplybook, Zoho Books, Vancity Business, Payworks

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of British Columbia — B.Sc., Computer Science

Sep 2000 - May 2003

For more information about me and my recent activities, please visit my personal site: <a href="mailto:calvincchan.com">calvincchan.com</a>